okay good morning haha i sleepy body is
here mind went home already
me too me too
let's do meditation
I think first mandalas good sock then
sock then I hear mandala from Malaysia
the big big boss of Malaysia
she ever hear her she meant our time
need a vision and an camp
some yes and maintain
and Cena
and you know
I'm injured I'm talking Sean um changer
part-time income sergey kurginyan
[Music]
um no not pinching some good buy some
Henchard are talking China
turn to binder that mean cavity
nagi-chan impasse sonam pension sang
[Music]
song adjourned
Sookie
turn to the kneecap Sergey nagi-chan
APIs and some thank you
something thank you for all your work
all here ok let's meditate cellphone off
Geshe Michael
ha
okay all the coffee is finished
[Laughter]
okay here we go
usually oh by the way if you want to
record it's okay if you didn't have
chance to make recording please just use
for yourself and don't put on the weight
yet okay
so usually we will start with the breath
we will watch our breath but in the
Mayan stance we start with the sound of
something in the room could be
refrigerator sound could be
air-conditioner sound could be the sound
of your family and your children in
another room so instead of fighting that
sound we will follow it and blew your
mind to the Sun and this is a good
beginning to focus your mind in this
room we have the air-conditioner son
let's listen to that
and then we go to the sound of our
heartbeat if you're in a very quiet room
you can hear the heartbeat inside of
your ears but when we're meditating in a
group I think it's easier to feel to
feel the heartbeat
now let's go inside the heart more quiet
place
and very beautiful lots of sunlight very
comfortable meditation room and the
walls of the heart are beating around me
and now go deeper to the center of the
heart it's like a room in the middle of
the room still lots of sunlight but it's
more quiet and it feels the sound of the
heart beating is far far away
and now we put our mind in a single
grain of sugar
tiny single point in the heart it almost
feels like I could get lost in the room
and when my mind goes inside it's again
a very elegant and beautiful sunlit
meditation room
now I'll expand my mind as wide as the
ocean you can imagine standing on the
beautiful beach here and looking out at
this beautiful ocean
and my mind becomes that ocean s why
there's the whole world
and now let's add the whole sky
my mind is as wide as the sky and the
ocean together
please remember to do the extra exhale
then your chest won't get tighten and
your breathing will be smooth at the end
of that normal exhale when the lungs
pause then push out a little more air
don't force it just a little bit
no we'll turn the mind off like turning
off a light if thoughts come then fight
them and send them out of the mind
level 8
turn off the mine but when thoughts come
to the mine don't fight with them don't
connect with them and just let them come
and go and stay very very quiet
so that's the warm-up on the meditation
it's like warming up our body before we
run a race it's not a real meditation
real meditation has to have a important
object the old Indian word for
meditation
it means that the thing you focus on you
will become done thing so breath is good
for preparing for meditation the
heartbeat and the sea and the sky these
are good for relaxing the mind but we
don't want to become those things so now
we start the real meditation choose one
of the teachers in your life
big big teacher is your mother or father
or you can choose a special
schoolteacher
the person who taught you your junk
could be your wife or husband has taught
you a lot your children teach you a lot
could be a historical teacher like
Buddha or Maitreya we have lots of
teachers it's like we have a big drawer
full of clothing and during the minute
when we start the meditation it's like
choosing what kind of pants do we want
to wear today
there are many choices so choose one
that feels good today one of your
teachers and ask them to come and sit
with you knee to knee real person not a
picture not a statue living person who
loves you very much they are looking at
you there are so proud you are
meditating
okay let's choose a teacher
now let's think of one quality of this
teacher that we really appreciate maybe
they are very patient
they never get upset maybe they have a
very good meditation practice maybe
they'd like to help old people and sick
people
maybe they'll always have a positive
attitude and and friendly to everybody
so pick pick pick one quality
now that quality is just like the pin
usually we think it's inside the teacher
and as we get to know the teacher we
begin to see the quality inside them
from the things they do or the things
they say but if all things are like the
pin then that beautiful quality I see in
my teacher isn't inside of them they
have it they really have it and there
are very good teacher because they have
it but it's coming from me the reason I
see it it's because I did something good
in the past
and when I did something good
I saw myself I heard myself and that
seeing and that hearing myself planted
the same so let's go on an imaginary
trip to our past life different country
different body could be male or female
could be even a bird but in that past
life maybe hundreds of years ago in
another country
I did good things to other people
happily and I saw myself to these things
and that seeing myself planted seeds
that's why I see my teacher now with
this good quality if I imagine what I
did to plant those seeds I am actually
planting more seeds to see this good
quality in my teacher so let's have fun
make a movie of your past life
enjoy the movie do many beautiful and
inspiring things in your movie
you are the hero or the heroine of the
movie make it beautiful
okay we'll spend some time here
didn't slowly come back to your teacher
enjoy their good quality again but in a
new way with wisdom very aware that this
is coming from my seat and very happy if
I'm good to other people if I continue
to plant these beautiful seeds which are
planted in my past life I can keep this
teacher in my life
and in many lifetimes they will always
have this beautiful quality I don't have
to be a perfect person everybody makes
mistakes everybody has bad days but
karma always grows small seeds make big
trees if I just do a few good things to
other people today it will grow and grow
and I will always be around this
beautiful teacher and there's no teacher
who doesn't come from me that was the
big wrong idea of my whole life I'm
waiting for other people to be nice to
me I'm rejecting some people I'm
choosing other people
because I think some of them have good
quality inside but there's nothing
inside
of other people there's only what I see
from my seeds then I ask that teacher
this is the most important thing you you
teach me is where my teacher comes from
and it would be nice if you could stay
with me all day
then when I have trouble remembering
where things come from when I get upset
or jealous let me remember you and
remember what you taught me if you stay
inside my heart that would be nice all
day and I can always ask you for help
so please come to my heart then the
teacher starts there very happy you
asked and they're like yeah yeah I'm
happy to stay in your heart and I'm glad
that you asked me and they start to rise
up into the air and they get smaller and
smaller and they come to the top of your
head and they become as small as your
thumbnail and they are facing the same
direction as you
you can feel the warmth of their body on
the tip of your head and ask them to
come down into your body they come down
slowly down that John mind the central
channel it feels like warm honey coming
down your spine
and then they stopped inside your heart
in that beautiful sunlit meditation room
and they will stay there all day and
they are ready to give us help that's
why it's important to meditate at least
a little bit every day because you can
bring someone to your heart who can help
you all day
okay let's come out of the meditation go
back to the mind turned off mine level
eight very quiet no fighting my thoughts
let them go
and now some thoughts come up just fight
them a little bit
and my mind becomes the blue sky in the
blue sea
then they see alone
then I'm in a sugar Krista
small elegant meditation room inside a
sugar crystal
then I'm in the center of the heart very
quiet inner meditation room
then I'm in the heart and the heart is
beating around me
then I'm in my body I'm feeling the
heartbeat in in this room three long
exhales we dedicate the good karma
meditation is a very very great karma
three long exhales
each one isn't golden light goes out to
the world touches all people brings them
happiness brings them understanding
where things are coming from three long
necks here
you can slowly open your eyes
take a good stretch I have something to
drink we're gonna need a microphone say
gee Nick couple microphones
any questions okay
[Music]
okay good question let me answer the
first question we don't think about it
but if if you think about it someone's
talking in your mind all day you know
it's a funny we usually don't think
about it sometimes it's good to to watch
this person talking in your mind like
sometimes I'm very surprised
unpleasantly surprised when I listen to
that guy in my mind you know
he's complaining a lot and I don't say
what I'm thinking but the thinking
sometimes it's not very nice you know
then one day might I told my teacher you
know because I think it's because of
meditation I started to listen to my own
to the person in my mind and I told him
I'm a little bit shocked you know
sometimes it he says very bad things
didn't I said you know in my bad person
he said no you are not the talker you
are the listener
you cannot talk and listen at the same
time my partner of Veronica she's always
telling me that you cannot talk Getty
Michael and listen at the same time
sometimes you should stop talking and
just listen to me
then I'm like oh yeah okay okay so you
cannot be the talker and the listener at
the same time so if you hear someone
talking in your mind it must be another
person and those are your seeds okay so
the seeds are opening I put seeds in my
mind last week when I gave pen to
Stanley and I carried those seeds in my
mind for one week
then this morning I came to the class
and I saw a pen on the table and that's
coming out of those seeds which I
planted last week and what's interesting
is the person talking in my mind it's
actually seeds and seeds are opening and
out of the state is coming talks so my
teacher said don't worry geshe michael
you you are not a bad person
today you are bad person last week you
planted those seeds and they are opening
today now I'll tell you something very
important I always teach the pen when I
go anywhere tomorrow on the airplane
when I sit next to somebody how are you
where you from
do you have family do you know about the
pan I always have pen in my pocket
so you know someone complained to me in
Singapore but they were not from
Singapore okay they're from Europe and
they came to me after the talk
you're getting all why you say that you
repeat yourself every year you forgot
you taught this already
you came to Singapore nine times you
taught to Penn nine times then we pay
money to come to hear you you should say
something new you know why I teach the
pin over and over in the gym it says if
you really understand the pin then when
you die you cannot go down okay cannot
go to hell cannot become animal cannot
become spirit impossible the person who
understands the pen they get contract
from Buddha okay no more hell for you
they signed Buddha sign that's general
explanation
if people complain to you you teach the
pen every year Edmond is so boring then
you can tell them this is why I teach
the pen but to be honest to get that
contract guarantee the pen is not enough
you need to understand deeper that your
own thoughts are coming from what you
did last week you are not a talker in
your mind you are the listener and those
talking coming out of seeds word by word
coming out of seeds and this is really
the core of me of Michael it's the
talker and the listener I'm not my
finger I will lose my finger
I'm the talker in my mind and the
listener in my mind and that talker and
that listener is coming from what I did
last week
okay if you understand that that's the
inner pen then you get the guarantee
okay everybody got it guarantee okay all
right but that's not her question her
question is I want to become a better
person getting that then last week I I
said something bad to somebody I plant a
seed then this week when I listen to my
the person in my mind of course they are
saying something bad then how to change
you see because the person today will
say something bad and that talking in my
mind will make a new bad seed in my mind
how can I change do I have choice or is
everything safe you know can I change my
direction or not okay and the answer is
I'll tell you a joke from I heard in
Europe in Germany okay you guys know
this one German professor in the college
they were debating free will did finally
he said we have no choice we must accept
free will okay anyway why you have free
will you have lived forever
and you will live forever actually you
cannot kill their mind you can change
the rental car but you cannot kill the
mind so your mind has been from
beginning this time at some time during
endless time someone will explain the
pen to you okay you will make small good
seeds there's a famous story a very bad
man was born as a fly and the flies best
food is a poopoo
and that fly landed on the poop Oh to
have a nice dinner then came a big
rainstorm there was a flood the flood
carried the poopoo and the fly is riding
on the then the flood accidentally went
around stupa so that fly run around
stupa he made some small good things by
accident then later because of that
seeing someone teaching the pen okay we
all have some small accident good thing
and then someone will teach us the pin
and then the direction then the free
will comes strong free will you can
decide what seed you want to plant okay
so we have free will we have it also
come from seed
okay thank you okay let's let another
person ask her question yeah guess she's
lost answers too slow I'm sorry
[Music]
okay you want to say question
okay Nick after this I'm gonna do three
presentations first one will be your
team your mixed nuts second will be CSP
pure gold and the third one will be DM
okay
so happy ready okay in that order
okay okay question yeah there are four
levels to the to the understanding of
the pin most important there are two
divisions this lower division is called
like physical objects to understand this
come from me
[Music]
so when you teach other people don't
start with the talking in the mind pink
always start with the pin okay because
it's easier to understand seed you start
from outer thing then if you get a very
smart group in Thailand and on the last
day you think they can go deeper then
teach them about the talking seed in the
mind the first part is understanding the
conquering of the object the second part
is understanding the cooking of the
subject and of these four levels it's
the third one where you get the
guarantee and that should be
understanding where's the thought coming
from in my mind
so if you reach this one you cannot be
born as an animal you have Buddha
guarantee and I think everyone in this
room has it okay so we did a good job
[Applause]
but what if I only went to the Singapore
talk geshe-la thought the pen for the
eighth time I'm not thinking about the
pen I'm thinking about how much money I
pay and why he teaching the pen again
[Music]
then I didn't reach this one then on the
way home I get a car accident so I heard
the pin but I didn't reach this one
impossible I will be born as an animal
okay so is that guy's animal birth
better than the animal birth of the
person who got in the accident coming to
the talk
[Laughter]
oh yeah it did unbelievable better they
call basketball animal Reaper good
translator yeah let's give my hand yeah
many days that they are tired okay they
are super tired it's extremely difficult
to translate live translation Geshe I
can think about the coffee but he cannot
focus and it's extremely exhausting I
used to do it from my teacher so we have
to thank all those traders shopping
Catherine Catherine
[Applause]
Steve Steve Steve Steve yeah and the
other chance honey thank you thank you
thank you thank you
cool hi Tony
funky Kate I'm fine okay so yeah basket
basketball animal rebirth it means you
will go down and then you die quickly
and come back okay we call basketball
remember that's a Buddha Buddhist were
not my room now if I'm doing Lance dance
meditation the first eight levels are
not meditation going like this is
there's no Olympic medal for a warm-up
but it's better if you do one
now his question is if I'm doing the
warm-up and I turn off my mind level
eight then there's an earthquake and my
house fall down and I die so where will
I go my suggestion don't spend a lot of
time on the first eight parts okay do
them a little bit quickly then if
there's an earthquake you are already on
level nine no just kidding in general
don't spend a lot of time on the first
aid level and try to go directly to the
ninth level okay and I mean spend most
of the meditation period on the ninth
level and I think there's another seed
that you can plant
many people are doing those first eight
levels and they think this is meditation
they came to the class geshe-la taught
the first eight then they went for
peepee during level nine they never
heard lover much did they only do first
eight level like watching breath
meditation these are the people who went
to PB during level nine they're just
watching breath it will make you more
calm but it won't keep you out of the
hell rounds okay it won't keep you out
of the animal room for that you must go
to level nine you cannot become a Buddha
with the first age levels okay so every
day you know I have to explain the eight
levels it takes me time but when you do
it yourself go a little bit quickly to
level nine
if you do that for thirty days and then
on the thirtieth day there's an
earthquake during level eight that seed
in your mind which is stronger is the
teacher and the past life so you would
not be born in a useless place because
you you spent a lot of time on level
nine in the first twenty nine days cool
okay thank you okay we'll start again
[Music]
maybe okay we're gonna do some more
numbing
here we go rocket awesome momentum meter
panel sociologists of Samos unencumbered
on Sargon rockin day so legit Sam
chenkin so there are very advanced
practice we call secret practice diamond
way bad Rihanna like Amitabha like that
special practice and there are special
practice for the key secret practice
when you come to Diamond Mountain like
Earl he did for three years
no talk just do the secret practice okay
then one day somebody asked my teacher
what is the secret practice and he said
that that's secret he won't give me
anything
but here the teacher said there's a book
and there's the automatic in the books
and teaching us go to the tennis shoes
to pursue it say that I'm much attended
De Anza gate reversibly to never who to
give us a cage relationship and about
unanimity you took an Alicia get to
takuna never my passion power like that
we have to memorize okay many many hours
okay
that's a book secret practice if you
come to Diamond Mountain
[Music]
people like our own people like Kelsey
who did the three-year retreat
they also did about seven years of
training in the book secret practice so
if you go to Diamond Mountain you can
learn it but the inside secret practice
I can teach you now okay and no anybody
can do okay three parts number one I'm
tired of things going bad I'm tired of
this party you know I have to feed it I
have to poo poo then I have to feel it
again they have to poo poo again then I
have to feed it again
I have to poo poo again and then inside
there I get sick each poop oh you get
older it takes a chi to make poo poo
each time you make poo poo you lose some
cheese some time the chief finish
and the puto also finished then buried
I'm okay it's strange to think you know
even just people we required she she has
to go here and push it out then you get
older so that's the first one three
principles for inner automatic secret
practice number one I have to change
this body I have to get a Buddha body
before it's too late
that's the first one second one
everybody around me right now gave me
milk from their breath in the past life
so there are same as my mom in this life
then they also die their body also gonna
die
if it's not my mom it's okay but it's my
mom my mom's don't I have to take care
of this I wanted to care of them how
many no count no count okay
not just your city not just your country
not just your world there's a story in
India before Buddhism called it's called
hito petition we have to study it in
Sanskrit class then there was a frog
from he lives in the well he's big firm
and he's very proud I'm the biggest frog
in this world I'm really important
person biggest frog then he made friends
with a crow so a crow will come to the
small village well to drink some water
then the Frog will talk to the crowd why
you drink water here I'm a king of this
world this whole world you have to ask
me if you drink water then the crow is
very wise okay
can I drink some water King okay
you can drink then they became friend
then he's always talking about he's the
big king of the world
finally the crow got a little bit
irritated he said you want to go for a
run you know you can see the other part
of the world outside this well there's a
little bit you can I can you can ride on
my back put your hands around the crows
Nicks
and hold tight and I will fly you can
see something then the frogs are okay
okay then the cross that I have idea you
know if you are looking everywhere maybe
you forget to hold on so I suggest you
close your eyes then frog said okay I
would do and he hold the cross neck and
crow fly because I don't open your eyes
maybe you were found you will fall down
he took him to the beach in India it's
called go alright go like this very
similar to this Beach he put the Frog on
the beach then he said I was count to
three then you open your eyes and he put
his face towards the ocean then the
cross and Sun are open your eyes to the
Father then his brain explode
he died right there this is the old
Indian story they're always like that I
don't know why Indian people like I
think it's a sad story but the second
step okay
first one for automatic secret teachings
I have to change this bunny then don't
think like frog in English we say don't
think small expand your mind if this
world has people and if you go out at
night our retreat center is the most
beautiful sky night sky in the world we
are two two hours from the nearest city
you can see like billion stars if this
world has Chinese guests came to our
retreat center
they come from Shanghai Shanghai you
can't see this guy even in the daytime
then they came they saw the first
nighttime they are like a fucker then
they say tomorrow also gonna be yeah
every day ok so there are many worlds
not just this one then statistically
should be this billion stars should be
other worlds so don't be like from don't
think Shenzhen is the whole world Los
Angeles is the whole room or don't think
this world is the only world when you
see conceived directly on that day you
will see all the worlds in all the
people it's very fun it's fun to go to
other country I love to see other cities
go to Ho Chi Minh see all interesting
things beautiful people then you feel
happy you know but imagine you can go to
countless worlds countless beautiful
people
imagine you can do that okay so that's a
second one
they all need to change the body and you
have to help them when you're a kid when
you're alone I think all of us I don't
know when you're about ten years old or
something you think why why I was born
in this place you know this country this
body this world well why was I born to
my mom and not to my friend's mom and
only ten year old is intelligent enough
to think about it before that you're too
young after that you're too busy ten
year old can think philosophy why did I
come here then there's a reason there
are countless worlds billions billions
billions of people they all have this
mistake body mistake
you know mixed seed buddy I'm alive I
have body that's good
I can go to Thailand I can go to pani
I'm lucky but it's also trouble it's
going to die so you have to think about
many planets many many people under day
that you see coming directly you will
meet them all the people on those other
planets you meet the Buddha but you also
mean all these people then you're like
that's the answer to the 10 year old
question that's why I came to this world
I'm supposed to become Buddha I'm
supposed to take care of billion billion
billion planets that's my job that's
what I'm supposed to do and each each
one of you you have Buddha seen you were
born with the Buddha see
and your personal responsibility is to
take care of billions of people so right
now we have difficulty to take care of
ourselves but if you see coaching your
ability changes you will take care of
billions of people
you will help them change their body you
have to hurry up okay many people
waiting for you okay so do your lions
dance every day especially think about
that kong king of the teacher where's
that good quality come from visit your
path now don't get nervous
okay but work steady every day touch
your meditation okay just touch it then
if you don't meditate you will feel so
guilty
[Music]
oh I touched my meditation Christian I
didn't do meditation when I touch it all
the Buddhists in the universe come there
Wow he couldn't meditate my teacher come
looking at me oh you gonna meditate then
if you don't meditate you feel so guilty
thousands of Buddha disappointed it's
like you invite someone to the movie you
watch one minute and you tell them to
leave
okay so just steady a little bit every
day Anatole has a naturally amazing body
he's a great yoga master before that he
was a great wushu master really and so
don't get fight with him okay I but I
don't have this kind of body when I was
born I look like basketball
[Music]
now I'm a little bit long basketball
then I'm not actually okay but I do the
yoga every day in my retarded way okay
and that's okay it's enough okay so try
to do five days a week meditation we are
not great meditation master we every day
we make big stupid mistakes but just go
every day to the cushion touch it one
thousand Buddha's will come then you
feel guilty if you don't do meditation
you waste a Buddhist time okay that's
the second one first one automatic
secret teachings I want to change my
body number two I have to change
everybody body
I have to change because they gave me
milk okay you cannot ignore your mother
after they give you milk it's your
responsibility to help them change your
body okay then the third part how how
will I get disability how can I develop
this ability Lyons dance part 9 you
think about coaching that's all just do
that you will wake up your Buddha scene
okay cool
then you know you can ring a bell
you can do the monitor training
that you can do all this thing secret
practice but if you don't have those
three it doesn't work okay it's like
Tesla car without a battery okay looks
good doesn't work okay it's better to do
the opposite get those three then
everything becomes secret teaching
automatic I'll tell you the structure of
the secret teaching hold whole structure
okay it's very beautiful very very nice
it's the best thing in my life okay
two parts first one tried to contact
Buddha or in Christian they call angel
try to contact angel learn to talk to
Buddha or learn to talk to Angel
directly where's the angel this is a
normal person okay where is the angel No
[Applause]
some angel answered the question
yeah is everybody but you have to change
your scene okay that's all you don't
have to go to other planets electabuzz
paradises in Thailand in the digit Thani
Hotel okay I understand just make the
seat you don't have to go anywhere so
that's a first level make contact learn
to talk to Angel that's a secret
teaching second second level they after
you make contact they will teach you how
to be like them okay they will teach you
this called kill him and Zagreb
my car killed him creation creation
first level Caucasian second level call
completion and all the secret teaching
in these two creation means a make
contact with those angels second one
they will teach you how to be like them
okay and you can change your body in one
lifetime okay cool
all right stamina machine named Tom and
Jesse on this immunity him okay we did
that already we reached a very big
section in the lung okay it took eight
years now we reach the important section
okay type a dip in longer long antenna
up how do I reach Buddhahood what's the
path
everything up to here is kind of like
preparation how do I reach Buddhahood
and before you reach Buddhahood
you have to reach what Nirvana okay not
the same thing
many people make this mistake
first you reach nirvana then you reach
Buddhahood
now I taught you the two husbands the
husband called her wife Phantoms then
the wife went to Thailand she didn't
fall asleep in the class she heard all
the pen
every day then when she went home
the husband then she feel you know if
you something come here right then you
you want to say something I'm not fat on
your fingers then but she went to the
Tyler Richmond she didn't sleep in the
class so husband say when she get home
then came that like this fire right we
all have it we all know I also have come
this one come first then after one
second this move
then between here you have to stop it
okay
he would say you went on you have sent
on this will go then the Chi come to the
mouth or your van
you have to stop the Chi here ready
you find Oh
okay understand okay
oh hey come from me now I'll show you
nip nip on you found on slow motion okay
ready you find them
okay that's nipple that's nirvana
okay okay so it's possible navona means
you stop your mouth later this one you
phantom
that's me fun when you can stop it here
okay when you get a habit you're very
like you should master okay that's
that's me bun okay
you don't change your body you don't
look different
there's a lower Buddhist school they say
when you reach me pon you disappear okay
not correct
okay it's a lower school or your mind
stop don't think like that
okay you look the same probably your
face is more beautiful because you you
never get angry now Buddha said
interesting thing there are many many
books in the world how to have a good
marriage
if you want to make good money write a
book about how to have a good marriage
because everybody means it every married
person means they will teach you many
things when the husband call you phantom
breathe deep count to ten this is a hot
photo like there are many thousand
methods Buddha sin and none of them work
okay they work for a few minutes then
you get angry okay the only one does
work if you understand the husband who
safe and tongue was never there okay
I'll tell you a story then you
understand so 19 years I work in the
diamond business then a monk I have to
live in the monastery
my company said we will give you
apartment in New York I said I cannot I
have to go back to the monastery every
night it's about two hours giant you
know I have to go back every night
then they said later they said okay we
give you a helicopter really they they
offer me helicopter not to buy the
helicopter but to use the helicopter
then I said no I don't want actually I'd
do my meditation on the bus so I like it
no I will take the bus then well I'm
tired you know it's about four hours to
go and come back and I did for nineteen
years then it's difficult and I'm tired
so five days a week
I don't sleep enough
then Saturday Sunday I will sleep until
noon maybe your life is the same I don't
know but that Saturday all the monks no
don't don't knock on gate last door
until 12 o'clock they will make a nice
breakfast for me called 12 o'clock
breakfast on Saturday so usually every
morning I get up around five o'clock
something I have to get ready and I
don't know if you work for the same
company for many years you put the alarm
clock you will wake up one minute before
the alarm clock wake up you don't have
to open your eyes you just stop doing
okay they get up go in the shower take
the car then maybe during the shower
your eye will open then get ready go to
work okay then
it's automatic sometimes on Saturday I
will forget it's a Saturday five o'clock
go to shower take the shower then the
shower
oh it's a Saturday I think go back to
bed
all wet you know just get back into bed
sleep until 12:00 then I live my
monasteries in cold place I don't know
if you have the winter a picture of the
temple in New Jersey it's a very cold
place in the winter
I have a special socks at that time I
don't have any money I have one good
pair of socks then I will get up twelve
o'clock put on the special stock go to
the bathroom water
there's the temple okay and beautiful
then Mongolia then there's a house
behind then I was stepping the water on
the floor not stupid monk don't know how
to close the door
and then I will go to the 12 o'clock
breakfast okay who took a shower this
morning
like that's about eight months you know
then a second one you took a shower no
third one he I know he didn't take a
shower
he has his manga his policy never take
shower in the winter in the spring he
smell a believer I know it's not him
then you guys know jumpa very very nice
man very sweet never say bad thing I
said jumper did you take
but you did yeah like oh my god I do I
put the water on the floor my staff then
the person that I'm angry suddenly
disappeared okay I understand
we never blame myself he's not stupid
put the water on the floor what's wrong
with you stupid we we always forgive
ourselves oh it's okay case you know you
work so hard
then the person I'm angry just disappear
oh that's confused
okay when their husband call you stupid
who put the water on the floor yeah my
sir didn't anger go okay Buddha says
this is the only way that a human being
can stop anger
[Music]
Herman permanently understand the other
person you are angry at doesn't exist
cannot exist
the anger has no nothing to be angry
then you your anger will start
permanently
that's NEPA that's Nirvana okay how to
know a person reached Nirvana when I was
a kid we have four brothers we call the
big guys and the little guys I stay with
my older brother and my two younger
brothers sleep together same room we
called big guys and little guys - and -
and we hang out together then why did my
mother have two more babies I'm on this
one
why did my mother have two more babies
after me just to make me angry okay this
is their full-time job to make me angry
and they're very good at this they can
do many ways many many ways and strange
they'd like to make me angry you know
they will do something then they see if
I get angry if I don't they have to
think of a new way they will break
something then finally our getting your
mind is the same your mind is the same
your mind wants to make you angry and
your mind will try a hundred different
ways to make you angry and can do if you
don't if you don't understand continue
the mind will make you angry okay that's
nippin so what's a Buddhahood is when
you change your body you get a special
body you can have billion people at the
same time
Nippon nobody can make you angry Duda
your body change you can go to billion
worlds at the same time okay you you
want to take a we have about 45 more
minutes we can take a small break or I
can just keep going what do you like
keep going okay if you need a break just
go okay if you have a pee-pee problem
just go if you step in something water
in the toilet if you step in some water
in the bathroom
don't forget who put it there okay did
it did I mess that are we okay
you okay jasmine okay okay okay all
right
my boss say okay okay double as soon so
finally we reached a section in the
lamrim after eight years what's the
actual path what can I do then double
awesome there are three parts to the
path
number one our trouble comes from anger
and other emotion okay bad emotion all
the trouble come from that so we should
study them we should study how does
anger work when I get angry how does it
start you know in my heart how does it
start
how does it grow how does it live here
how does it stay okay we should study
our enemy the art of war he said know
your enemy study your enemy first angry
second part how to stop it
how to stop it and then number three how
does the anger cause your body to die
okay how does that emotion make your
body to die so we're going to do these
three subjects here and Bali and Bali
and Bali and I hope Hawaii okay we see
if we make enough seeds okay
first part study those negative emotions
there's a four parts four steps number
one let's identify all the negative
emotions there are six okay there are
six big enemies then number six there
are five kinds some ten enemies
mainly ten enemies let's study them okay
let's study anger let's study jealousy
let's study desire let's learn what
their face look like so we can shoot
them okay that's the first part second
part how did they start in my heart
what's the steps that I get angry in the
first moment second moment third moment
fourth moment
how does anger get strong
that's a second subject third one who is
their mother okay who create them where
did they come from can I can I stop that
part and then number four what will
happen to me if I don't fight with these
enemies if I don't well what will happen
to me if I don't fight them up to now
they are living in the country of my
mind
they control my mind if I get angry all
all my good thoughts have to stop so
it's like this enemy control the whole
country called Michaels mine
and since I was young they live here and
they controlled this country so what
will happen if I don't fight it's like
other country attack your country like
in World War 2 Japan attack America
aside China and America Japan take over
China then our anger desire they took
over when we were born it's not their
country but they control how to kick
them out and if you don't kick them out
what will happen in this country
ok cool all right all right those are
four steps number one what those guys
look like if they say kick this soldier
out of Shanghai you should know don't
shoot the wrong one how did they get
here
then you know what Causton and if I
don't kick them out what will happen to
my country
okay this for like a war it's like a war
conjunct away during Sunday's such as
this such an Amana Java dunk image of a
loony abandoned Ernie Dane York et
cetera but the pendulum antenna up a nom
de Mond
yep I you know there's two ways to teach
these four subjects and he's going to do
it the second way and I'm not going to
talk about it yet kay on our Karachi
dance o Soniya mix sample cover the
engine turn the key when a data call you
can get a dog named do good search any
more Shepard Cheney taken should you we
have to identify them and we have to
find out where they came from
it's like foreign army took over your
city if you want to fight them you
should know what they look like
don't shoot the wrong people
okay then I continue like naked content
on your mum be continued
so let's study the enemy there are two
armies the enemy has two armies one my
bad sees one my bad since second the bad
feeling that create those bad seed
in my mind okay
like those six enemies how many six and
this one has five so ten okay cool
alright neo- oculto go paddle a kid
chasing laden your mom became why we
have this kind of body which will die it
comes from both of those enemies it
comes from both of those enemies yes
number one my bad scene number two the
bad feeling I have which create those
panties so the enemy has two parts we
have to fight both of them Nara
shockingly Tommy you're constantly
taking your mom base and then Manor land
intervention now this is very important
we have countless bad seeds from past
life
okay do we have any good seats yeah
what's proof we're here yeah good okay
okay I have ears I have eyes I'm in
Thailand I'm listening to learn them are
you special there's a seven billion
people who need to change their body
only 500 are here so nowadays in the
world people will say you know geshe-la
I'm depressed why I'm a little bit fat
and I'm also Bob so I wish I had more
hair I wish I'd look like a Natal
but you know I'm a little bit depressed
I'm not beautiful like other people here
just kind of normal person I have I feel
like normal person I'll tell you a story
I'm sorry but it's a good story
so there are two most famous doctors in
West China
traditional doctors okay
one of them came to New York then irises
translator for several years and it was
a great honor I learned a lot I remember
then medical translation is difficult
traditional medicine
there are many words I don't know then I
learned a lot
one word comes from india called GU GU
GU you from India sorry did I say India
yeah come from Sanskrit
then he said if the patient has glia
problem you should give them this herb
then I'm like I don't know what Sakuya
he said Greece Greece I'm like I don't
know it's good he said okay just say
Guha for now so I said if you have GU
your problem then later one very wealthy
woman invite him to her apartment in New
York and she's very little bit like
sixty years old
very elegant you know and she'd like
wearing gold clothes we went to treat
her I was a translator then he said he
checked you know they do this thing you
know three fingers here on three
different Jing and he showed me what
there's a many fluttering pulse and
rushing pulse and then he said he told
her I need to check more
she said okay what what I have to do go
peepee right now in the glass then she's
very rich in the glass yeah yeah in the
glass this is what you know and she went
in the bathroom it's very quiet
did she come out she's very embarrassed
you know she's got then me and the
doctor are like they use chopsticks they
will go like this and check how many
bubbles no no not not like that then
then he goes Wow
I said well she Kaguya
look this is GRU yeah then she's like
she doesn't want to show her peepee you
know he's so happy we got real Kuya here
to translate for him then he will take
question and answer
we gave teaching to like hundred people
then somebody asked him in traditional
medicine what's the cause of cancer you
know how can we stop cancer what what
helps cancer to grow then he said you
know your lifestyle we were in New York
your lifestyle is a problem the food you
eat processed food and especially the
chemical which they put in the food to
keep it from getting old
like why does watermelon stay in the
store for three months and doesn't get
old there's a many chemical on it you
know so he said you are you are giving
yourself cancer and another condition
which is dangerous you are driving all
these cars
you know I said oh is it exhaust
pollution no no not bad
it's the tires you have to buy new tire
every year he said why why you have to
buy the entire every year they wear out
he said where does the rubber go which
wears off the tire you know 100 million
cars that rubber goes into the air in
your city you're all breathing rubber
rubber causes cancer that's what going
on you know this is the these are the
condition for cancer then he said later
he said anybody have questions one guy
raises hand so you said what cause
cancer is the food and the air in our
city New York yeah what normal people
what are we supposed to do you know what
are we supposed to do we should stop
breathing we should stop eating you know
what are we supposed to do if this is
the cause of cancer Tennyson I didn't
say it was the cause of cancer I said it
was the condition it it helped the
counter grow he got little angry at me
I'm translator and I never said it was
the cause of cancer I said it was the
condition for cancer and I'm I'm
confused you know Emily what's the cause
of cancer cause of cancers are easy you
don't love other people in New York
you're not buddy stop you are not
thinking like buddy suffer of course
that's the cause of cancer this other
thing just helped the cancer you don't
love each other that's it that's the
problem that caused her cancer and I'm
like wow he's supposed to be just a
doctor
Wow then he's got a little bit angry and
he's like also you'd said another bad
thing
first I want what you said what are
normal people supposed to do you know
what are normal people supposed to do
don't call yourself normal you are not
normal okay seven billion people in the
world today you heard the word
Bodhisattva don't call yourself normal
you are not normal person you're special
special person today you heard the word
body stuff he got angry don't kind of
stuff no no today you heard the word
body suffer you must be special you must
be special person you must have special
karma to be in China okay
understand okay cool
so there's a two divisions cause and
condition okay cause and conditions for
a tree the cause is a seed Christine
cause for apple tree is the Apple seen
okay then the condition it's a water
fertilizer sunlight the cause for cancer
is you don't love other people in your
city that's a cause of cancer
what's the condition chemical in your
food
rubber in your air pollution these are
conditions now will the tree grow from
the seed if the condition is missing
yeah if the apple seed is there if you
put apple seed on this stage and it
doesn't get watered it doesn't have soil
no sunlight will that tree grow no okay
good so there's something you should
understand about bad scene in your mind
okay the state who make your husband
angry the seat that caused your husband
to talk back to you or don't give you
hug when you want her okay there's a
main scene maybe you yelled at your kids
oh you didn't hug your kids enough so
the CDs is there okay
bad scene is there but if the bad seed
doesn't get water doesn't get sunlight
the husband will never call you bad word
understand so I'll say it again apple
tree comes from Apple seen to make an
apple tree apple seed needs water it
needs sunlight if you have apple seed
but it doesn't get sunlight or water it
will never go through if you yelled at
your kids last week then you have
yelling husband seed in your mouth but
what a book saying now
Ceylan manor
london - asunción say sellin sellin
manor
london tower Sobhan shin okay but you
yell at your kids if that seed never
gets water and sunlight
it will never open now something you
have to know about seeds inside the mind
the seed stays in the heart chakra seeds
are stored here okay and you have
billions billions of seeds are waiting
to open the space they take it's less
than the tip of a needle
billions of steam in the inside the
heart chakra in the space is smaller
than the tip of a needle if they get
water and sunshine
your husband will yell at you if they
don't get water and sunshine your
husband will not yell at you it's like
you put the apple trees seed in the
freezer it will never open okay it it's
not gone but it will never open so I
will teach you two ways to put the seed
in the freezer okay ready
[Applause]
you you heard in DCI for powers that's
the usual way so I will repeat it then
I'll tell you the special way okay and
then that's enough for today so here we
go it's called for powers
to put the seed in the freezer
sometimes when you teach it to new
people you can say here are four ways to
destroy the scene but actually it's not
correct you cannot destroy a comma see
not possible why because the law of
karma is more powerful nobody can stop
it
Buddha cannot stop it okay what is the
law of karma if you hurt someone you
will be hurt if you help someone you
will be helped even Buddha cannot fight
with this law even Buddha living this
law and then no one can break it and now
actually that's good okay try to imagine
what will happen if this is not true so
I live in a small town
we have farmers death they we have one
coffee shop it closed at two o'clock
okay it's so small time after two
o'clock
you cannot buy coffee in my time and so
I will go there and these farmers they
are talking you know they have special
English you know
hey Jade what you got when you can
supplant this day why are you doing it
Oh JA not done plant some corn you can
master corn
yeah I don't got lots of corn then we
also don't understand half of their
language but imagine the farmers are
meeting in my turn would you plant this
year I planted corn yeah watermelon I
plant the corn but a watermelon Kim Oh
too many watermelons
[Music]
imagine this is farming imagine you
plant a seed but you don't know what
will come out you plant apple seed you
get banana okay
imagine try to imagine Karma's the same
okay you cannot say bad word to your
kids
you're almost stupid kids in Shanghai
then the result must be similar husband
must the other you nobody can change
that Buddha cannot change them but
Buddha taught us how to put a bad scene
in the freezer it doesn't break the law
of karma it just keep the seed we are
open forever
that's good
okay all right four steps step number
one think about the pen very simple just
think about the pen okay that's all if
you want to put the bad scene in the
freezer for stairs we don't call for
steps we call for powers they have the
power to delay the seed from opening for
a bar okay so number one just think
about the pen you know and your kids
then that automatically leads to power
number two why think oh my kids come
from seeds my awesome my husband also
come from seeds if I yell at my kids and
I put a bad scene in my mind that bad
seed grow 100 percent every 24 hours
yell at the kids on Wednesday by
Thursday the husband has to yell at you
once by Friday he has to yell at you
twice by Saturday he has to yell at you
four times by Sunday he has to yell at
you eight times then you feel oh I gotta
cut this I gotta cut this before Monday
it's 16 you know that's the second step
I must cut this team okay I must put it
in the freezer quickly
it's a doubling every 20 for my cancer I
have to put it in the freezer quickly
that's the second step
okay what's the third step I wish I had
never planted this seed I'm not gonna
ever do this again I will never yell at
my kids again that's see step one latest
step to automatically step to lead to
step three automatically I will never do
this that's the main freezer for the
scene this side I will never do this
again okay
I will never yell at my kids again is it
true
impossible okay your kids are normal
kids days sometimes they have bad day
of course you will yell at them again if
you do step number three i will never
yell at my kids again you're gonna make
another bad scene because you will yell
at them again so the great teachers for
the last two thousand years they said
make time limit make a time limit okay
two hours I won't yell at my kids then
if you want you can put some tape on
your mouth for two hours okay make a
time limit but don't break it so make it
for two hours I want the other my kids
that's the main energy that puts the
seed in the freezer when you design I
will not do this for two hours that's
the main power puts the seed in the
freezer
okay then step number four power number
four make some balance
okay balance our karma like if you
yelled at your kids yesterday
then decide today I will tell my kids
one good thing about my kids then go in
the kids room
mommy yelled at you yesterday I said you
are the worst kids in in Shenzhen but
actually you're the most beautiful kids
in Shenzhen I'm so lucky to have you
okay so if you balance the Karma balance
a bad seed with a good sea power number
three is a promise not to do something
for a certain amount of time power
number four is a promise to do something
okay
understand different number three is
negative number four is positive okay
then these are the ways to put a seed in
the freezer
guess not how much I have to do how many
days I have to do
when I was young in college before I
became Buddhist I had a abortion later I
found out it's a mistake then I asked my
teacher you know how can I clean this
thing how could I put this seed in the
freezer because actually I killed a
person very serious yes so I said how
can I put the seed in the freezer then
he gave me a suggestion to start our
children's class buddhism class for
children and I did I said how long I
have to do he said until you get the two
science that that seed is in the freezer
there are two signs that the seed is in
the freezer
okay it's good to know the sign okay
first one comes from gin country comes
from by the way is some child is playing
two children are they're playing I
taught this in New York one time
about before I did my own three-year
retreat
I thought shouldn't do abortion from my
own experience then I did three retreat
when I came out of retreat I thought
again in New York and I have special
waiting room called Green Room you know
I can hide from the people I can think
about what I have to teach you know so
I'm in the green room and a hundred
people are coming and the girl small
girl came in the room and she's all pink
like one of these girls today she's all
in pink you know and looks like and
she's dancing and then then her mother
came in you know so I'm sorry she came
in your room I'm sorry I don't mind it's
beautiful
she's very beautiful did she look at me
she says this girl exists because of you
three years ago I came to your teachings
I was pregnant I was thinking you have
abortion because of your talk I didn't
have a boy because of that she's alive
tonight and she said it's a happiest
thing in my life so anyway I asked my
teacher how to so he said you will get
two sons first one is in the teen
context when the seed moves to the
freezer it will open a little bit okay
like if I put a sequencer on this stage
and it opens a little bit if I put water
no sunlight it will open a little bit
little piece will come out and then it
will die okay it won't make a tree or it
won't make ten watermelon okay people
come out and then it will die
so King Kong King said if you made the
Karma to have a cancer
which is like abortionist is that kind
of cover then instead of that result you
will get a sudden unusual headache for
like a whole day that serious seat just
open a little bit then you will get a
very bad headache for the whole day
somebody put this teaching many years
ago they put on a cd-rom I I taught the
four powers they made a CD room they
gave too many people then one lady call
me Asian I have to tell you story what's
the story I was driving my car down the
Pacific Highway it's the most beautiful
Highway in America it goes next to the
Atlantic Ocean through Los Angeles very
beautiful drive and again I was
listening to your CD about that for
power number one think about the pen
then I also thought about the pen
everything comes from my scenes so
automatically I think about power number
two
what bad seed do I have and how fast
it's growing and automatically that lead
to power number three you know I should
make a promise
did she thought I would make a promise
right here in the car I will promise not
to do again and she's still listening to
the then you should balance the Karma
and she said okay I will help some kids
you know then she reached the part we
reached now to science the seat is in
the freezer
number one sudden small problem instead
of cancer you will get one day hold a
headache which you never had in your
life and she said when I got to this
part smoke start to come out of the car
in the car catch on fire jump out of the
car whole car burn up and my bad see how
something on she's still happy you know
she's like
then I send all message you know first
time she said two things I need number
one what's the second sense because the
CD burner second time you will feel like
free from an old problem
okay suddenly your heart will feel like
sunshine you will feel much younger and
very happy because nothing on your mind
suddenly you feel very young very joyful
and that's the second time that the CDs
finish then I said what's your second
question she said I think because you
taught this teaching you should send me
the replacement CD for free
because you burn up my first CD okay I
was okay last thing then we finish and
this is a good place to stop and I'm
gonna make
okay the sunlight and the water for a
bad seed is not understanding the pen
the person who understands the pen took
away the sunlight and the water from
their bad seeds all the time all their
bad things okay so that's why if you
understand the pen well you cannot
become animal you see okay
connection if you understand the pen
well you took away the sunshine you took
away the water those bad seeds can all
grow the one which take you to animal
which take you to hell so just thinking
about your beautiful relapse almost
everybody I saw 26 groups or something
almost everybody's going like there
I like it okay when you go like this you
are taking away the sunlight you are
taking away the water for all your
pencils
okay cool so keep burning okay thank you
[Applause]
well I need